<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Nelson Gil Vargas</title>
    <link>https://nelsonalejandrov.github.io/Nelson_Portfolio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Nelson Gil Vargas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nelsonalejandrov.github.io/Nelson_Portfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project IV: Telecom Customers (Clustering)</title>
      <link>https://nelsonalejandrov.github.io/Nelson_Portfolio/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nelsonalejandrov.github.io/Nelson_Portfolio/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>Created a hierarchical clustering, to help a telecom industry company, to find groups of clients who use their services in a similar way. This customer segmentation can be used to propose an specific service plan for each type of customer. Having 1000 customer observations with the variables: average number of hours of calling per month, average number of hours spent in international phone calls, average number of text messages sent per month, average data usage per month in GB and the age of the user in years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project III: Credict Scoring (Regression)</title>
      <link>https://nelsonalejandrov.github.io/Nelson_Portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nelsonalejandrov.github.io/Nelson_Portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>Created a credit scoring model using linear regression in R. Worked with 300 records of users, including the variables: income in thousands of USD, credit scores, number of credit cards that the user owns, the age of the user, the education level of the individuals, the gender of the client (male or female), student factor (yes or no), married individual (yes or no), ethnicity of the individual and the average credit card debt of the individual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project I: Customer revenue</title>
      <link>https://nelsonalejandrov.github.io/Nelson_Portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nelsonalejandrov.github.io/Nelson_Portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Worked with 51243 observations of customer purchases to a business. Each of these observations has three variables: customer_id, purchase amount and the date of purchase.    From the data of purchase I extracted the year and the days since the purchase was made. With the use of the sqldf library, which allows the manipulation of a dataframe with SQL queries, I grouped the last day of purchase and the average amount of purchase of the customers with the same ID.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project VI: Tweets&#39; Sentiment Analysis (Natural Language Processing)</title>
      <link>https://nelsonalejandrov.github.io/Nelson_Portfolio/post/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nelsonalejandrov.github.io/Nelson_Portfolio/post/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>Created a Tweet Sentiment Analysis code with NLP techniques and a logistic regression model in Python. For this I used numpy, pandas and nltk libraries. I used the Tweets dataset included in the nltk python library, which includes 10000 Tweets: 5000 &amp;lsquo;positives&amp;rsquo; and 5000 &amp;lsquo;negatives&amp;rsquo;. I splitted this dataset using an 80% as a training set and the other 20% as a test set (to assess the accuracy of the model).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
